<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>electro on :   Code  :   Cad   :   Carve  :  Create :</title>
    <link>https://riganti.com.au/tags/electro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in electro on :   Code  :   Cad   :   Carve  :  Create :</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright: Mark Riganti `{year}`</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://riganti.com.au/tags/electro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ReDuplicator MK3x - Wanhao i3 overhaul</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/mk3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/mk3x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is a complete overhaul of the original Wanhao i3 with a few main objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep the core components of the printer while upgrading its structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create maximum rigidity through a sturdy 3030 Aluminium extrusion frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow for future proofing and commonality of parts by basing all printed parts on the current Original Prusa MK3 files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the weight of the X and Y carriages where possible to improve print speed and quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/master/Pics/1%20Glamor%20Shots/main.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;noooice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wanhao i3 is a fabulous printer, but new generations of printers have begun pushing the boundaries. It has become apparent that in comparison, the Wanhao has a few deficiencies. Deficiencies which we will address in this project. The key improvements of this upgrade include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better rigidity through 3030 extrusions and metal brackets. Even with my or Azza’s excellent z braces the printer was still susceptible to slight wobble, especially under twisting forces (pull left tower and push right tower). When moving the printer it would require constant releveling due these small movements. Now i can barely get any movement using my full strength.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comfortably increase Z height to ~200mm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce noise. By not screwing the motors directly onto the metal frame, motor vibrations and noise is reduced significantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move towards more standard Prusa files for future upgradability, but with added strength improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modular hotend, This design allows for the hotend to be replaced easily replaced without disassembling the printer. I have created a Titan Aero mount as an alternative to the original MK10 with a E3DV6 mount incoming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sturdier 4 bearing Prusa style X-gantry. Not sure if it was specific to my printer or a common Wanhao problem, but my X gantry always had a lot of wobble which may have been a source of printing artifacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noticeably better print quality due to a combination of everything above. I am able to print faster with better quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Wanhao i3 variants and rebrands are compatible, however the plus will require additional work to create an enclosure for the electronics. This project can also be built from scratch, or salvaged from other printers as long as measurements are altered accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK3x/blob/master/Pics/1%20Glamor%20Shots/PrintDemo.webp?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Oh hai&#34;&gt;
Sample Print @~100mm/s on the titan aero extruder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/master/Pics/1%20Glamor%20Shots/side.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oh hai&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample of improved print quality. 0.24mm layer height @ 70mm/s (titan aero).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/master/Pics/1%20Glamor%20Shots/boaty1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;boatyMcboat&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will be maintained both at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:2686588&#34;&gt;thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;. The files were created using a combination of Fusion360 and tinkercad. They can be viewed and edited via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tinkercad.com/things/azPlfmHU5MQ#/&#34;&gt;this Tinkercad link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table Of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/1.--Bill-Of-Materials&#34;&gt;1. Bill Of Materials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/2.-Printing-Parts-&amp;amp;-Pre-Assembly&#34;&gt;2. Printing Parts &amp;amp; Pre Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/3.-Base&#34;&gt;3. Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/4.-Begin-The-ZTower&#34;&gt;4. Begin The ZTower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/5.1-Hotend-MK10-Original&#34;&gt;5.1 Hotend MK10 Original&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/5.2-Hotend-Titan-Aero-Upgrade&#34;&gt;5.2 Hotend Titan Aero Upgrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK3x/wiki/5.3-Hotend-Hemera-upgrade&#34;&gt;5.3 Hotend E3D Hemera Upgrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/6.-XAxis-Gantry&#34;&gt;6. XAxis Gantry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/7.-Complete--the-ZTower&#34;&gt;7. Complete the ZTower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/8.--YAxis&#34;&gt;8. YAxis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/9.-Cabling&#34;&gt;9. Cabling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/wiki/9.1.-Recommendations-&amp;amp;-Future-Dev&#34;&gt;9.1. Recommendations &amp;amp; Future Dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-and-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Thanks and Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/prusa3d/Original-Prusa-i3&#34;&gt;Prusa Research MK2s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1692666&#34;&gt;Datvr&amp;rsquo;s Prusa MK2S-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1246425&#34;&gt;Thorped&amp;rsquo;s excellent Wanhao Fan Duct &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1635585&#34;&gt;Cyul&amp;rsquo;s spool holder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.0 - Initial Release&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.01 - Updated idler files with multiple z endstop mount points for upcoming Titan Aero upgrade. Sturdier cable cover box. Added 1Meter GT2 belt to BOM as the stock belt may not be long enough (can anyone confirm?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.02 - Updated the &lt;strong&gt;Part Fan Bracket&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Part Fan Bracket V1.1&lt;/strong&gt; The original doesn&amp;rsquo;t align with the carriage plates properly. Please print the revised one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.03 - Uploaded a new Y Carriage Belt Holder. This one is based on the current MK3 design and is much easier to fix and tension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.04 - &lt;strong&gt;X Gantry Idler 9MM V2&lt;/strong&gt; was missing the heat-sert insert holes to mount the cable box. Updated and fixed with &lt;strong&gt;X Gantry Idler 9MM V3&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have already printed V2, you can keep the part and manually drill 2x 4mm holes spaced 9mm wide and 6mm deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.1 - 11/03/2018 Major Prusa MK3 Update. This updates an update of many of the original MK2s based parts to MK3 Based parts. This includes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MK3 Based Part Cooling shroud and mount. It performs much better than the original Thorped based one. flawless @60 degree overhang with some sagging @70 degree overhang. The original would show artefacts &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/master/Pics/9%20Titan/overhang.jpg&#34;&gt;@60 degrees.&lt;/a&gt;. Almost comparable to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/3Dprinting/comments/7kexdv/a_nearly_comprehensive_study_of_cooling_fans_and/&#34;&gt;Dii Cooler.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much improved X Carriage. This uses the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/master/Pics/4%20Hotend/CarriageNew.jpg&#34;&gt;MK3 belt mounting method&lt;/a&gt; which is much easier to install under tension. The whole extruder assembly can now also easily slide on and off the rods to greatly simplify installation and maintenance. 16mm M3 screws are used to secure the bearings. I&amp;rsquo;ve also made and tested changes which allow the extruder assembly to be built without heat-serts and can be substituted with M3 nylocks. NOTE: due to these changes the Rear carriage plate is NOT compatible with the existing Front extruder plate as the hole spacing has been changed. The New Front extruder plate must be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front Extruder Plate. Better spacing around the hotend to improve the filament path. Updating Hole Spacing to be compatible with the new Rear Carriage Plate. Strengthened BLTouch mount. Increase spacing around heater block to reduce residual heat. Not compatible with old extruder plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X Axis Motor Mount. Incorporates the new MK3 design. Better Spacing to ensure a straighter belt path. Includes new MK3 tensioner to easily tension X belt. Requires M3nS Nut and 20mm M3 screw. (Enough tension can be applied by without the M3nS) Installation is similar to the Prusa instructions &lt;a href=&#34;http://manual.prusa3d.com/Guide/4.+Z-axis+assembly/509?lang=en&#34;&gt;here, steps 11-18.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this project  contains dozens of files already, Older retired files are retired to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/tree/master/STLs%20Reduplicator%20Core%20Parts/Retired%20Versions&#34;&gt;Retired Versions directory in github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.1.1 - Endstop Part For sensorless homing with TMC2130 Drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2 - 05/11/2018 - Multiple improvements based on Prusa MK3 R3 release. This includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prusa MK3 R3 based part cooling shroud. This gives a noticeable improvement over the original shroud. Also improved the clearance between the shroud and the nozzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved X Carriage rear plate. This was strengthend to better handle bumps and knocks. Rigidity is also improved. It is still a common part between the MK10 and titan aero extruders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengthened Z Rod Securer parts. Some people had issues with these snapping in PLA but should no longer be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.3 - 17/02/2020 - E3D Hemera mount. Updated fan duct to the most recent R4 release. Added an angle for increased rear fan duct clearance. This will filter down to the other hotend designs shortly. Initial update of parts across to fusion 360. A number of parts have been converted and this will continue over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/blob/master/Pics/10%20Hemera/HemeraMain.jpg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved cable mounting system by clipping onto the X axis motor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/blob/master/Pics/8%20Cables/CableMotor.jpg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.3.1 - 19/02/2020 - MK52 Removeable heatbed Mod - resized rods and extrusions to accommodate the prusa MK3 heatbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/OmNomNomagon/ReDuplicator-MK2sx/blob/master/Pics/11%20MK52%20Expansion/Mk52Main.jpg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converging LED Floor Lamp</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/lamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After spending months unsuccessfully trying to find the perfect floor lamp, I decided to make one myself. This design makes use of two &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ikea.com/au/en/catalog/products/50403184/&#34;&gt;Ikea SPANST LED light bars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Two light bars overlap in a visually appealing fashion and is the perfect brightness at night. The 3d Printed mounts fit directly into a finished wooden base. I used Australian Red Ironbark coated in danish oil. eSun Silk Brass is a perfect filament to complement the dark red grain of the wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Bill Of Materials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ikea.com/au/en/catalog/products/50403184/&#34;&gt;2 Ikea SPANST LED light bars&lt;/a&gt;.  134cm versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Countersunk Screws. 4g 15-18mm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wood for a base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25mm Boring Drill bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2mm Drill bit for pilot holes if you are using a hardwood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose any layout you feel looks good, but here are the measurements I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base: 350mm x 190mm x 20mm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holes for the mounts: 25mm Diameter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Length Distance Between Mount holes: 160mm (Center to Center)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Width Distance Between Mount holes: 34mm (Center to Center)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Used 5 Degree Mounts. However 6 Degree mounts are also included in case you prefer additional overlap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Power and Additional Details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lights are powered via USB. See my Related Sonoff USB box project if you would like to be able to use this lamp with google Assistant / Alexa or use RF wall switches to turn it on from anywhere in your room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also quad braided the cables using paracord for a cleaner look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lamp pairs perfectly with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4166314&#34;&gt;sonoff USB smart enlcosure&lt;/a&gt; to power the lamp. It allows for google assitant / alexa voice control and has the ability to turn the lamp on and off with paired 433 wall switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloadable on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4166209&#34;&gt;thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MK52 Heatbed Expansion</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/mk52/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/mk52/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonoff Dual USB</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/sonoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/sonoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an enclosure to combine a Sonoff R2 Basic RF switch and usb dual output charger.
The USB charger used is a cheap and easy to source YJ-128. The PCB&amp;rsquo;s for both the Sonoff and charger are press fit into the base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design features a prominent button for on/off and resetting the switch, strain relief for the input cable, and a thin port where the indicator light can shine through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This device is perfect for pairing with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4166209&#34;&gt;Converging LED Floor Lamp project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4x 8mm Countersunk M3 screw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 8-12mm Button head M3 Screw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sonoff Basic R2 RF smart switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dual USB charger Model YJ-128&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloadable on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4166314&#34;&gt;thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom K65 RGB Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/kb1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/kb1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Drevo Calibre</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/kb2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/kb2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wanhao 24v Gen-L TMC2130 upgrade</title>
      <link>https://riganti.com.au/project/controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riganti.com.au/project/controller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Adaptor to convert the electronics of a wanhao i3 to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MKS Gen-L&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspi 2/3/b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mosfet with 8mm x 63mm hole spacing, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliexpress.com/item/New-3D-Printer-Heated-Bed-Power-Module-High-Current-210A-MOSFET-Upgrade-RAMPS-1-4-12V/32811898708.html?spm=a2g0s.9042311.0.0.um477z&#34;&gt;this one.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Adaptor fits on top of the existing mounting holes and is secured with M3 screws and washers. The  boards are mounted with M3 screws of a length of 3-6mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place a piece of carboard or foam under the control board to prevent shorts.
Pics and a marlin 1.1.8 config for a working MKS Gen-L and TMC2130 are also included. Due to the cramped spacing in the case, the usual USB Type A cable will not fit without being modified. The rubberised plastic shield needs to be removed to allow the cable to bent enough to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup works perfectly with Octopi, and the TMC drivers run cool and quiet with sensorless homing.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.3dcampy.com/2017/12/20/tutorial-instalacion-y-configuracion-driver-trinamic-tmc2130-en-ramps-y-mks-gen-1-4/&#34;&gt;This guide&lt;/a&gt; contains a great TMC2130 wiring guide. The Gen-L is the same except the AUX-3 Header is rotated 180degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I ran a RAMPS board, but it required a lot of modification in order to run at the 24v required for the Trinamic Drivers. After it died the GEN-L was a great cheap substitute that can natively handle the 24v without modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend switching out the rear fan with the included 120mm adaptor to keep everything cool as the TMC drivers can generate a fair amount of heat. This shroud is as thin as physically possible. It is 5-15mm shorter than other designs. It has the power port on both the left and right sides. It works when the control box is stand alone and can be flipped 180 degrees to allow for mounting the control box to the bottom or a lack table. The other electrical port hole can be plugged with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1710028&#34;&gt;this thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When replacing the mainboard, the original wanhao display will not work without rewiring the ribbon cables. Alternatively the Reprap Discount full graphic smart controller is a drop in replacement. With this configuration the SD card is built into the display and will be blocked when mounted into the case. however this isn&amp;rsquo;t an issue when printing via octopi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloadable on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:2895849&#34;&gt;thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
